What is going on guys and welcome to javascript tutorial for beginners in this course we'll learn what
is javascript how to add javascript to our project how to write javascript and at the end we will build
few simple projects to see how javascript works.
Beyond syntax and theory as always if you have any questions you can find me and you me or on YouTube
channel coding adek.
First things first.
What is javascript.
Javascript is a programming language and not just some regular programming language.
In fact javascript is the de facto programming language of the web.
So if you would like to become a web developer you will have to learn javascript.
Although it is subjective.
Javascript is considered the most popular programming language in the world.
If the HD model is responsible for the structure of the web page and C Ss is responsible for styling
of the web page javascript is responsible for the functionality of the web page.
For example an event occurs only when the user presses the button.
Lets say some kind of annoying pop up window shows up not only javascript is the king of the web now
days.
Javascript is everywhere.
It works on the server side.
For example no.
I guess it works on games and tons of other places.
Another great bonus of javascript is the fact that it is easy to learn.
So let's not waste our time and lets start learning javascript.